TRAVIS J. JONES SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

Targeting an Internship or Entry-Level Opportunity in Software Engineering.

Recent graduate of Lamba Academy of Computer Science, offering a strong foundation in software engineering and programming principles across multiple technologies.

I am a proactive, organized, and punctual individual who is an enthusiastic team player, a deep creative thinker, quick learner, sharp troubleshooter, and possess strong analytical and research capabilities.

Experience

Lambda Academy of Computer Science · Software Engineer

Oct. 2017 to April 2018 · Remote

An intense, full-time CS Fundamental/Software Development Program.

- Mastered all curriculum coursework including React, React-Native, Redux, NodeJS, Express,
- $Mongoose/MongoDB, MySQL, Python/Django.\ Mocha, Chai, and\ Jest for\ Test\ Driven\ Development.$
- Hands on experience with client and server testing, paired programming, and CS fundamentals such as Data Structures, Algorithms, BigO, Operating Systems, Computational Theory, and low-level languages like C.
- Utilized agile software development and Git workflow on all projects
- Approached all coding challenges using pair programming
- Utilized Full MERN Stack Web Development

Buzzles Concessions, LLC · Technical Supervisor

March 2015 to Oct. 2017 · Spring, Texas

- Conducted mechanical repairs and maintenance of machines as well as conducted periodic location evaluations to ensure the quality of product and efficiency of workflow
- Assisted in any/all aspects of the company including training staff, customer relations, and onsite events.
- Maintained and updated POS systems, hardware devices, and related equipment
- Responsible for installing and managing remote security systems.

Animal Clinic of La Porte · Office Manager

April 2013 to March 2015 · La Porte, Texas

- Effectively managed daily operations of the clinic while sustaining excellent organizational skills to ensure efficiency of all aspects of the clinic.
- Handled many of the building's maintenance operations, managed security systems, and developed various marketing strategies to improve sales.

Projects

Hey-Team Standup Bot March 2018 to May 2018

Hey-Team is a Slack Bot utilized to streamline team standup without disturbing the overall flow of conversation. Made for teams and workspaces in the Slack environment.

- Worked on backend development and server-side routes to handle the flow of data with Express and Node.js and dealt with structuring the database using MongoDB
- Used the Slack API to build the bot, the Stripe API to accept payments, and the SendGrid API to send emailed receipts and reminders
- $Hosted\ Link-https://heyteam.net lify.com/ \\ Github\ Link-https://github.com/Lambda-School-Labs/hey-team$

EnerTree Dec. 2017 to Current

EnerTree is an Energy Plan search application that helps you find a reliable, efficient plan that fits your budget. It is a personal project that is still a work in progress with many more feature to be implemented.

- Integrated with PowerToChoose API for energy plan information
- Github Link- https://github.com/CosmonautJones/energy_search_project

DevConnect April 2018 to Current

DevConnect is social networking web app for developers to connect and display their skills and experiences with other developers.

- Utilizes the MERN Stack with Redux, and uses the Github API to show latest Github repositories for that user. Soon to be hosted on Heroku.
- Hosted Link https://developer-connector.herokuapp.com/ Github Link https://github.com/CosmonautJones/DevSpace

Education

Lambda Academy of Computer Science

Major in Software Engineering 2018

San Jacinto College

Electronics Technology and Communications Engineering A.A.S. 2015

Contact

281-245-4591

♥ Houston, Tx

in travis-john-jones/

CosmonautJones

Skills

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

JavaScript

HTML/CSS

React

Redux

MongoDB Mongoose

NodeJS

Express Git

Unix

TEST-DRIVEN DEVELOPMENT

Mocha

Chai Jest

CS FUNDAMENTALS

Data Structures

Algorithms

Computer Architecture

Big0

Activities

Lambda School Hackathon - callApp ·

Jan. 2018 to Jan. 2018

A 24 Hour Hackathon working to build a video chat application.

- Worked with React for the Frontend with authentication for signing in.
- Github Link https://github.com/Lambda-hackathon-video-chat-app/callApp

2nd Lambda School Hackathon - Socializin July 2018 to July Full-Stack Developer 2018

The second ever 24-Hour Hackathon hosted by Lambda School. As a team of 3, we built a web app designed to help find free time between your friends and family to allow yourself to connect with one another with ease through busy lifestyles.

- Worked on the database for user/event info and the API to connect to it
- Worked on frontend gathering the data and displaying it
- Built the landing page and improved on the React Calendar
- GitHub Repo:

https://github.com/LambdaZombies/socializin

- YouTube Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch? v=qq9Ak6JJz2M

Arduino Workshops at TX/RX Labs · Participant

This workshop demonstrated the Arduino's operation and features. We got to delve into hands-on development, learning how to use common sensors and program the Arduino platform. An incredibly fun course that gave insight into understanding basic Electrical Circuits and how microcontrollers worked.